Guide to the Steven Chu Papers SC0828
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional papers, Accession ARCH-2013-061
  - Publications
    - Quantitative Measurements of Force and Displacements Using an Optical Trap, 1996 Apr (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - The Manipulation of Biological Molecules with Light, and Abstract for The Optical Trap as a Tool for Measuring the Actin-Myosin Interaction, Undated (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - In Vitro Methods for Measuring Force and Velocity of the Actin-Myosin Interaction Using Purified Protiens, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Atom manipulation based on delayed laser pulses in three- and four-level systems: Light shiftrs and transfer efficiencies, 1994 Sep (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - Direct Observation of Tube-Like Motion of a Single Polymer Chain, 1994 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Proposal for optically coolinng atoms to temperatures of the order of 10^-6 K, 1986 Feb (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - Three-Dimensional Viscous Confinement and Cooling of Atoms by Resonance Radiation Pressure, 1985 Jul 1 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Precision Measurement of the Photon Recoil of an Atom using Atomic Interferometry, 1993 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - Linear Pulse Propoagation in an Absorbing Medium, 1982 Mar 15 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Thermodynamics of Positronium Thermal Desorption from Surfaces, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - 1997, Precision Atom Interferometry with Light Pulses (Box 6, 6, Folder 8, 8)
    - 2001, Progress towards a Measurement of h/MCs (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 1994, Atomic Interferometer Based on Adiabatic Population Transfer (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Positronium III, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Lectures and presentations
    - Laser Trapping, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Raman Velocity Selection, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Surface Scattering, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Older College Viewgraphs, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Cold Sprg. Harbor Course, 1995 Sep 95 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Charge Neutrality, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Titin, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Reptation, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Hairpin Ribozyme, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Ribozyme Folding, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - General Single Molecule, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Single Molecules, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Humanities Seminar, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Normal Modes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Fret #1, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Fret #2, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - The Quantum Vacuum, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Physics at Stanford, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Misc. Optical Tweezers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Optical Tweezers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Single Molecules, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Polymer Talk, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - General, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - RNA Junction / Mg 2t, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Siegman Symposium, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - ID Experiments in molasses, Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Figures for Loeb Lectures, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Muonium, PS logistics, Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Exec. Viewgraphs, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Parity + EDM, Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Recent Ps, Undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Historical (Early Viewgraphs), Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Laser Cooling 1, Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Figures for Trapping, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Trapping Photos, Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Collisions, Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Dipole Traps, Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Magneto-Optic Trap, Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - COLD Cs2 Collisions, Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Atom Tunnel, Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Physics + Biology, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - APS Centenial (Asian Physicists), Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Beijing Speech, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - The Manipulation of Neutral Particles, 1998 Apr 7 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Nobel Lecture, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Suface Scattering Talk, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Talk at Spin Pol. Quant., 1988 Jul (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Ps, Mn Talk, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - PS 1S 2S Figures, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - PS 1S 2S Talk, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Polymer Elasticity Theory, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - The Physics of Time, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Pulse Propogation Talk, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Saturation Spectroscopy, Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Weisskorf Lectures, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Laser Cooling Theory / Experiment, Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - High Energy Physics, Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - CW PS Figures, Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Raman Cooling, Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - g- Measurement, Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Interferometer, Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Clocks, Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Nobel Viewgraphs, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - General Colloquium, Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Systematic Tests, Undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Cooling Misc., Undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Muscle Opt. Tweezer, Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Ribosomes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Biology / Tweezers, Undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Helicase, Undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Misc. Presentation Overheads, Undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Grants
    - Defense University Research Instrumentation Program (DURIP) Proposal, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Department of Energy Grant Proposal for Optical Manipulation of DNA, 1990 Feb 01 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Air Force Office of Scientific Research (AFOSR) Grant Renewal in Support of "Cooling and Trapping of Atoms and Particles", 1991 Sep 01/1994 Aug 31 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Instruments and Renovations Grant, 1997 Jul (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Berkeley Bio Grant for Physical Studies of DNA Using Microscopy and Optical Tweezers, 1997 Sep 30 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - AFOSR Grant for Atomic Clock, 1991 Aug 01/1993 Jul 31 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - NIH Training Grant Renewal, 1998 Feb 20 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Renewal of AFOSR Grant for Coolimg and Trapping of Atoms and Particles, 1998 Jul 16 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - NSF Grant Progress Report, 1996 Oct 02 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - National Science Foundation Grant Budget Statements, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - National Science Foundation Grant for Studies in Spectroscopy and Quantum Electronics, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - AT&T Bell Labs Proposal for "A Proposed Cold Pused Source of Atoms for Atom-Trap Loading", 1984 May 09 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - National Reconnaissance Office Grant for High Brightness Atom Sources of Atom Interferometer Gravity Gradiometers, 2001 Mar 30 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - National Science Foundation Budget Proposal, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - National Science Foundation Grant Proposal for Multidisciplinary Research in Optical Science & Engineering, 1996 Sep (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Department of Energy Grant related to Human Genome Project, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Atomic, Molecular and Optical Physics (REU) Supplement, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - National Science Foundation Grant for Studies in Spectroscopy in Quantum Electronics, 1991 Feb 12 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Budget Documentation for work at W.W. Hansen Laboratories, 1988 Oct 18 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Fabrication Number Requests for Various Laser/Optical Equipment, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Biology Proposals: SEQ, FEL, and others, 1992/1994 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Unrestricted Account Balances, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - AFOSR Grants, 1994/1997 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - National Science Foundation Grants, 1994/1999 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Human Frontier Science Program Grant for Polymer Physics and folding of single biological molecules, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Final Technical Report for AFOSR Grant for Cooling and Trapping of Atoms and Particles, 1994 Oct 01/1997 Oct 01 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Human Frontier Science Foundation Grant for Single Molecule Mechanics using Optical Tweezers, 1993 May 01/1996 Apr 30 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - AFOSR Grant for Cooling and Trapping of Atoms and Particles, 1991 Sep 01/1995 Feb 02 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - AFOSR Augmentation Awards for Sciencec & Engineering Research Training (AASERT) Paperwork, 1998 Apr 01/1998 Jul 31 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - AFOSR Progress Reports, 1998/2001 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Packard Foundation Interdisciplinary Science Program Proposal for Single Molecule Analysis of Biological Processes: From Simple to COmplex, 2000 Jul 01 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Supplement for NSF Proposal for Studies in Spectroscopy and Quantum Electronics, 1991 Aug 05 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - National Science Foundation Grant Proposal for Polymer Dynamics and Biophysics with Single Molecules, 1999 Jul 01/2002 Jun 30 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - AFOSR Budget Proposal, 1988 Jun 01/1991 May 31 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - NSF Proposal with Arthur Schawlow, 1991 Feb 01 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous Grand Proposals and Renewals, Undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Students and colleagues
    - L.J. Wang, 2000 Jul 20 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Jorg Schmiedmayer, 1997/1999 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - G.V. Shlyapnikov, 1990/1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Arthur Schawlow, 1975/2004 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Arthur Schawlow Obituary, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Arthur Schawlow Memorial, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Sanjeevi Sivasankar Thesis, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Rodrigo Esquivel Teixeira Thesis, 2005 Mar (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Hazen P. Babcock Thesis, 2001 Aug (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Thomas Tupper Perkins Thesis, 1997 Jul (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Mark Raizen, 1990 Sep 11 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Orly Alter (1 of 2), Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - A.P. Alivisatos, 1997 Mar 10 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Joachim Frank, 1998 Sep 24 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Stephen J. Kron, 1997 Nov (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Carlos Bustamante, 1990 Jan 26 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - W. E. Moerner, 1993/1999 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Tom Cech, 1999 Jun 9 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Taekjip Ha, 2002 Aug (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - S.J. Bennison, 1997 Dec 16 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Yaakov Shevy, 1990 Dec 01 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Martin Weitz, 1998 Nov 29 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Ania Bleszynski, 2000 Jan 30 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Steven Quake (1 of 2), 1999 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Steven Quake (2 of 2), 2000 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Tom Perkins, 1999 May 22 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Charles Adams, 1993 May 20 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Arjun Yodh, 1988 Mar 4 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Wayne Volkmuth, 1995 Mar 27 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Orly Alter (2 of 2), Undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Anita Goel, 1994 Dec 4 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Dolores Bozovic, 1994 Sep 12 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Cristopher Myers Niell, 1993 Jan 21 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Andras Vasy, 1990 Sep 26 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Stephen Ronald Quake, 1989 May 03 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Nir Davidson, 1993 Dec 07 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Mark Welling, 1996 Feb 29 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Kurt Gibble, 1992 Nov 28 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Doug Smith, 1992 Oct 21 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - David Weiss, 1993 Dec 20 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Lubert Stryer, 1967/1978 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Stephen Quake Thesis, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Veronique Lieber, 1999 May 4 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Andrei Papocivi, 1995 Dec 19 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Undergrad Recommendations, 1990/1992 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Aparna Bhatnagar, 1996 Aug 27 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Mark Kasevich, 2000 Jun 28 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Vladan Vuletic, 2003 Jun 11 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Physics Grad Students, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Physics Grad Students, Undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Post Docs, Visiting Faculty, Undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Quan Long, 2000 Jul 8 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Scott Blanchard, 2003 Mar 12 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Rotation Students, Undated (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Secretary, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Alex Cable, 1986 Aug 01 (Box 5)
    - Recommendations, Undated (Box 5)
    - Physics 320 Class #2, 1988 (Box 6, 6, 6, Folder 14, 14, 14)
    - Physics 320 Class #1, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - 1999, Recommendation letter from Professor Jacob Klein on behalf of Rafael Tadmor (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - David Scott Weiss Dissertation, 1993 Jan (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Brenton Christopher Young Dissertation, 1997 Jan (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Achim Peters Dissertation, 1998 May (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Michale Sean Fee Dissertation, 1992 Sep (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Posters
    - Nobel Prize in Physics, 1997
    - Nobel Prize in Physics: 100 Years
    - Nobel Prize in Chemistry
  - Professional Files
    - AFOSR Proposal, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - DNA Proposals, 1990-1992 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Geballe Professorship, 1988-1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - PPG Stuff, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - X-Ray/Optical Photon Parametric Conversion Proposal, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Ribosome, 1992; Laser Cooling and Manipulation of Atoms, and Selected Applications (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - IUTAP, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Larson Simulations, 1964-1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Forbidden Transitions, Electron Optics Lectures by Chris E. Kuyatt (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Forced 08C Dye Laser (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Mollasses Photos (Box 6)
    - PRL Review (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - ICOLS, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Microscopy (Near Field), 1988 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Ni NTA Coatings, 1993-1997 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Guggenheim Fellowship, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Book Offers, 1988-1998 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Fundamental Constants, 1968-1970 (Box 6, 6, Folder 36, 36)
    - Steven Chu's Physics Classes/Assignments/Exams (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Atomic Force Microscopy Papers, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Brownian Dynamics Simulation of Single DNA Molecules in Shear, 1999 Aug 19 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - New Limits on the Electron Electric Dipole Moment from Cesium, 1989 Aug 28 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Atomic Physics Papers and Lectures, 1999/2001 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Te Proton Momentin Bohr Magnetons - and All That, Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Papers by Herwig Kogelnik, 1964/1966 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Stochastic Problems in Physics and Astronomy, 1943 Jan (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Bell's theorem: experimental tests and implications, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Visualization of protien S1 within the 20S riposomal subunit and it's interaction with messenger RNA, 2001 Oct 9 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - The Unreasonable Effectiveness of Mathematics in the Natural Sciences, 1959 May 11 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Ungar Calculations, Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Polymer Imaging, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Purcell/Berg Motors, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Tom Perkins Calculations, Undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Opitcal Coolng to 10^-6 K, Undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica Article on Spectroscopy, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Notes and Articles on Brownian Motion, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Bead/DNA Attachment, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Popular Press Articles about Steve Chu, 1978/1986 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Dalai Lama Ephemera, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Honors and Accolades Ephemera, 1991/1993 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Science of Art, 1994/1995 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Cantilevers (AFM), 1993/1996 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Park AFM, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Misc. Graphs, Blueprints, and Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Debbie Stine - Storm Clouds on the Horizon: Setting the Course for America's Future Prosperity, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Associative memories based on message-bearing optical modes in phase-cojugate resonators, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Acoustic Microscopes, 1974/1978 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Journal of the Optical Society of America B - Optical Physics, 1985/1989 (Box 7, 7, Folder 29, 29)
    - Confocal Microscopes, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - DNA Dyes, 1989/1990 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Goodwin Articles, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Publications on Eletrophoresis, 1989/1996 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Tunneling Microscopy in DNA, 1989/1990 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Fluorescence correlation spectroscopy notes and letter, Undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Articles on Interferometry, 1985/1999 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - CPIMA, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Latex Particle Ephemera, 1988/1989 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Avidin-Biotin Renewal, 1985/1989 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Index of Refraction Effects, 1989/2000 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Nobel Nominations Ephemera, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Chen Institute Director Search Notes, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Aluminum-coated Pyrex double-ellipse laser cavity, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Bio-X Initiative, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Laser Spectroscopy Conference, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Bio-X To Do stuff, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Supermolasses, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Bio-X New Graphs, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Bio-Physics Notes, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Interferometer Patent, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Oscillator Blueprints/Papers, 1973/1978 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Misc. Notes and Exercises (1), 1992 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Misc. Notes and Exercises (2), Undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Atom Optics Review Papers, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Dipole Trap Notes and Correspondence, 1984/1985 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - ICOLS XV, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - InterAcademy Council Papers, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Old Laser Cooling Figs., Undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Bills for the House of Representatives Science Committee, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Misc. Publications with Steven Quake, 1996/2000 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Atomic Fountain RF Spectroscopy, Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Atom Trapping in Atomic Physics, Undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Radio Lectures, Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Atom Trap Data, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - X-Ray Notes and Publications, 1937/1978 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Diffusion Notes, Undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - The Current Status of Lepton g Factors, 1972 Apr (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Recent Developments in the Comparison Between Theory and Experiments in Quantum Electrodynamics, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - G2 Talk, Undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Atom Trapping in Atomic Plays X, Undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Polymer Physics Notes and Papers, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Misc. Notes and Exercises (3), Undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Misc. Notes and Figures (1), 1980 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Misc. Notes and Figures (2), Undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Misc. Notes and Figures (3), 1981 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Misc. Notes and Figures (4), 1983 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Misc. Notes and Figures (5), 1983 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Misc. Notes and Figures (6), 1979 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Misc. Notes and Exercises (4), 1988/1989 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Misc. Notes and Articles, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - On propagation of Gaussian beams of light through lenslike media, 1965 Dec (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Personal
    - Japan/China '88, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Misc. Speeches, 1998/1999 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Teaching Evaluations, 1988/1989 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Teaching Evaluations, 1998/1999 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Travel Receipts, 1988-1997 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Technically Useful Stuff, 1985/1993 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Faculty Reports, 1985/2000 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Safety Memoranda, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Humboldt Award, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Nomination for Nobel Prize in Chemistry, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - UC Berkeley Physics Classes Notes and Exercises, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - 1992-1993, King Faisal International Prize (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - 1993, 1993 King Faisal International Prize for Science (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Photos, 1987-1997 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Job Application - Curriculum Vitae, 1977-1987 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - National Academy of Sciences Meeting 131, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Humboldt, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Moving Records, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Audiovisual
    - NIST Colloquium Series, "Looking at Biomolecules...One at a Time", 2000 Dec 08; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Nobel Century - Nobel Science: Debate 2001, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Bioapplications of Nanotechnologies, Spring 2002 Seminar Series, 2002 Apr 4; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Science in Action, Undated; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Science Frontiers - "Super Lasers", Undated; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Spectroscopy at the Lunatic Fringe, 1987-1988; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Polymers in Shear Flow, 1999; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Steven Chu: Nobel Prize Demo, Undated; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Laser Cooling & Trapping: From Atomic Clocks to Watching Biomolecules Move, One Molecule at a Time, 2002 Feb 22; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - The Scientist: Super Laser + The Laser: A Light Fantastic, Undated; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Polymer Physics. S. Chu, Stanford Univ., Undated; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - RNA jxn folding, Helicase, Lipids, 1999; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Sortened demo of polymers, Reptation, oil stretch, violin string, 1995 Oct 10; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - View Graphs for Steve Chu, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Polymer Physics, S. Chu, Stanford U., 1999 Jan; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Edited Nobel Banquet, Undated; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Steven Chu: Exploring Polymer Dynamics with Single DNA Molecules, 1997 Dec 01; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Polymer Physics + High Strain Rate. S. Chu, Stanford Univ., Undated; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Mind and Life X - Day 1. Morning Session, 2002 Sep 30; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Mind and Life X - Day 1. Afternoon Session., 2002 Sep 20; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Mind and Life X - Day 2. Morning Session, 2002 Oct 01; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Mind and Life X - Day 2. Afternoon Session., 2002 Oct 01; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Mind and Life X - Day 3. Morning Session., 2002 Oct 02; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Mind and Life X - Day 3. Afternoon Session., 2002 Oct 02; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Mind and Life X - Day 3. Question & Answer Session., 2002 Oct 02; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Mind and Life X - Day 5. Morning Session., 2002 Oct 04; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Mind and Life X - Day 5. Afternoon Session., 2002 Oct 04; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 10)
    - Stanford Science: Laser Tweezers: A New Way to Grasp Matter with Steven Chu, 1998 Oct; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)
    - Optical-tweezers-induced defectsin 2D colloidal crystal (ling/brown)., Undated; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)
    - Arthur Schawlow excerpts, 1999 Jun; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)
    - Nobel Stadshus Band 3, 1999 Nov 11; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)
    - Nobel Minds, 1998 Jan 13; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)
    - Nobel banquet, 1998 Jan 23; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)
    - Nobel portratt Fysik+Kemi, 1997 Dec 04; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)
    - Copy of Polymer Demonstration, Undated; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)
    - Energy Transfer in the Bacterial Photosynthetic Unit. Theoretical Biophysics Group., 1999; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)
    - Steve Chu Intro, 2000 Dec; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)
    - Unlabled (1), Undated; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)
    - Unlabled (2), Undated; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)
    - Unlabled (3), Undated; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)
    - Canal 9 TVV. Entrega Premios Rey Jaime I, 2001 Sep 27; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)
    - Unlabled (4), Undated; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)
    - Unlabled (5), Undated; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 11)